A Guide to the Robert Young Clay Papers, 1789-2010 (bulk 1920-2007)
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Clay Family Research Files., Extent: 97 boxes. (Box 1-97)
  - Subseries G. Notebooks., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 68-81)
    - Volume 12 - Samuel Clay. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Volume 13 - Thomas Clay. (Box 70, Folder 7-11)
    - Volume 13 - Thomas Clay. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Volume 13A - Thomas Clay. (Box 71, Folder 2-6)
    - Volume 13B - Thomas Clay. (Box 71, Folder 7-9)
    - Volume 13C - Thomas Clay. (Box 72, Folder 1-3)
    - Volume 19A - Mary Clay Lockett. (Box 72, Folder 4-5)
    - Volume 19B - Mary Clay Lockett. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Volume 20A - Eleazar Clay. (Box 72, Folder 7-11)
    - Volume 20B - Eleazar Clay. (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
    - Volume 21 - Rev. Charles Clay. (Box 73, Folder 3-9)
    - Volume 22 - Thomas Clay of Kentucky. (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Volume 25 - Matthew Clay. (Box 73, Folder 11-12)
    - Volume 26 - Green Clay. (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Volume 27 - Sir John Clay. (Box 74, Folder 1-3)
    - Volume 29 - Wooldridge. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Volume 30 - Green. (Box 74, Folder 5-8)
    - Volume 31 - Thomas Clay. (Box 74, Folder 9-10)
    - Volume 33 - Jesse Clay. (Box 74, Folder 11-12)
    - Volume 33 - Jesse Clay. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Volume 33A - Jesse Clay. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Volume 35 - Daniel Clay. (Box 75, Folder 3-7)
    - Volume 36 - John Clay. (Box 75, Folder 8-9)
    - Volume 38 - Charles Clay. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Volume 38 - Charles Clay. (Box 76, Folder 1-4)
    - Volume 39 - James Clay. (Box 76, Folder 5-6)
    - Volume 40 - Allen Clay. (Box 76, Folder 7-9)
    - Volume 41 - Percibal Clay. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Volume 42 - T. Clay (Frederick?). (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
    - Volume 43 - Clay Family of Russell and Smyth Counties, VA. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Volume 1 - Clay - First Five Generations. (Box 77, Folder 5-9)
    - Volume 1 - Duplicates. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Volume 1A - Clay Chronology. (Box 78, Folder 1-2)
    - Volume 2 - Charles Clay 1341. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Volume 4 - Cabaniss. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Volume 5 - William "Mitchell" Clay. (Box 78, Folder 5-6)
    - Volume 6, Part 4 - Thomas Clay. (Box 78, Folder 7-10)
    - Volume 6, Part 5 - Abia Clay. (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Volume 6, Part 6 - Marston Clay. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Volume 6, Part 7 - Rebecca Marshall. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Volume 6, Part 8 - John Clay. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Volume 6, Part 9 - Lucy Clay. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Volume 6, Part X - Elijah Clay. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Volume 7, Part 1 - Mary Lockett. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Volume 7, Part 2 - Eleazar Clay 13532. (Box 79, Folder 7-10)
      - Eleazar, John, Mary, Edward - Chesterfield County. (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Rev. Eleazar. (Box 79, Folder 12)
      - Akin. (Box 79, Folder 13-15)
      - Ashbrook, Thomas. (Box 79, Folder 16)
      - Burfoot, Lawson. (Box 79, Folder 17)
      - Cheatham, William P.. (Box 79, Folder 18)
      - Clay, Henry M.. (Box 79, Folder 19)
      - Clay, Matthew. (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Clay, Matthew B.. (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Clay, Nancy E. Ashbrook. (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Clay, Phebe Newby. (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Clay, Phineas W.. (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Clay, Samuel. (Box 80, Folder 6-7)
      - Cole, Haley. (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Cole, John. (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Graves, Dorcas Clay. (Box 80, Folder 10-11)
      - Graves, Charles. (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Graves, Charles C.. (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Graves, William A.. (Box 80, Folder 14)
      - Gregory, Joseph. (Box 80, Folder 15)
      - Bob Long's Notes. (Box 80, Folder 16)
      - Snelling, Jane E.. (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Swepson, Richard. (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Trabue, Macon. (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Turpin, Harriet. (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Whitehead, Benjamin. (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Volume 7, Part 5 - Thomas Clay. (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Volume 7, Part 8 - Matthew Clay. (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Volume 7, Part 9 - Green Clay and Part X - Priscilla Clay and Martha. (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Volume 9 - Amey Clay. (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - Volume 11 - Charles Clay. (Box 80, Folder 26)
    - Volume 13 - James Clay. (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - Green Family. (Box 80, Folder 28)
    - William Clay and Ann Old. (Box 80, Folder 29-30)
    - William H. Clay and Susan Ann Brooks. (Box 80, Folder 31)
    - Charles Clay and Sarah. (Box 80, Folder 32)
    - Clay, Allen - Hallifax and Pittsylvania Counties, VA. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Clay-Cabaniss. (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
    - Charles Cabaniss. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Clay-Green-Williamson. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Clay, William - Chronology. (Box 81, Folder 6-11)
  - Subseries H. Photographs., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 82-84)
    The photographs contain images of Clay and allied family members, and are arranged alphabetically. There are also unidentified group photos, negatives, and photo albums. There are also numerous photographs of Clay's hometown of Dixon Springs, Tennessee, as well as homes and other buildings in Smith County, Tennesssee, and the University of Tennessee in Knoxville.
    - Alexander, Elizabeth. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Archives Staff, ca. 1980. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Baber, Nora Escue. (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Ballow. (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Beasley, Charles. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Bedwell, William F.. (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Biddle, Robert N.. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Blumberg, Fred and Natalie. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Bransford, Mrs. and Martha. (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Bridgewater, Benton. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Clark, Eliza Craighead. (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Charles Ransom. (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Marston. (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Martha Sharp. (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Paul Carrington and Martha Ann West. (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Paul Hogan. (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Robert Bell (and friends). (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Robert Young. (Box 82, Folder 18-20)
    - Clay, Ruth Young. (Box 82, Folder 21-22)
    - Clay, Ruth and Blanche. (Box 82, Folder 23)
    - Clay, Samuel. (Box 82, Folder 24)
    - Clay, Thomas - Home in Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 82, Folder 25)
    - Clay, William Young and Annie Kittrell. (Box 82, Folder 26)
    - Clay, William Young - Family at Peyton's Creek Home. (Box 82, Folder 27)
    - Clay, Wirt. (Box 82, Folder 28)
    - Corum Hill School - Sumner County, TN. (Box 82, Folder 29)
    - Darnall, Aurelia Hamilton. (Box 82, Folder 30)
    - Dixon Springs, TN. (Box 82, Folder 31)
    - Dixon Springs/Smith County, TN - Buildings, etc.. (Box 83, Folder 1-4)
    - Dixon Springs, TN - Clay Family Burial Plot. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Dixon Springs, TN - Flood. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Escue. (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Gann, Bessie Day. (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Gann, Roberta Price. (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Gibbs, Will and Mary Kittrell. (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Gwaltney, Millie (and family). (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Herod, Peter Clay. (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Hix, Etta. (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Keith, Paulette. (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Kittrell, Bryant and Wife and Cousin Oscar. (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Kittrell, Jennie (Fugit/Byers). (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Kittrell, John Bell and Julia Ann Elizabeth Ballow. (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Kittrell, Norman and Dodger. (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Kittrell, Robert (Grandmother Clay's Brother). (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Lowry, Joe. (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Manley, Nyeta "Nita". (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Paschall. (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Peabody Library School Graduation. (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Radford, Stephen W.. (Box 83, Folder 24)
    - Smith, Norma Dean. (Box 83, Folder 25)
    - University of Tennessee, Knoxville. (Box 83, Folder 26)
    - Wells. (Box 83, Folder 27)
    - West. (Box 83, Folder 28)
    - Young, D.D. (et als.). (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Young, Frank and Gracie. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Young, Frank and Odell. (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Young, Henrietta Jane Escue. (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Young, J.B. - Store. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Young, James Robert. (Box 84, Folder 5a)
    - Young, Joe. (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Young, Levy. (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Young, Norma. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Group Photos. (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Negatives. (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified. (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Photo Album. (Box 84, Folder 12-14)
    - Photo Album. (Box 166)
  - Subseries I. Card Files., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 85-94)
    There are numerous card files that were kept by Clay to aid in his research, including indexes to his notebooks, descendants of specific individuals, Clay marriages, deaths, and tax records, and cards that were never typed in final form or filed.
    - Name Index to Volume 1 of Clay Family Notebooks (incl. Identification Number and Spouse's name). (Box 85)
    - Descendants of Isaac Kittrell. (Box 86)
    - Smith County Soldiers. (Box 86)
    - Index to Henry Young Book. (Box 86)
    - Alpha Name - Typed But Not Filed. (Box 87)
    - Alpha Name - Not Typed or Filed (also Chronological and Alpha Cards and Miscellaneous Marriages and Deaths). (Box 88)
    - Descendants of Thomas Clay of Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 89-90)
    - Index to Allen Clay Volume. (Box 90)
    - C.C. Clay. (Box 90)
    - John Clay 13641. (Box 90)
    - John Clay 13431 and Anna Clay Clemens 13432. (Box 90)
    - Daniel Clay of Halifax County, VA. (Box 91)
    - Ballow Marriages. (Box 91)
    - Clay - Amelia and Nottoway Tithable Lists (Alpha/Chronological). (Box 92)
    - Index to Clay Deeds. (Box 93)
    - Descendants of Paul Carrington Clay. (Box 93)
    - Clay and Allied Families. (Box 94)
    - Unidentified Index. (Box 94)
  - Subseries J. Microfilm., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 95-97)
    There are various groups of microfilm in the collection, including issues of the Carthage Courier from 1913 to 1968, and deeds and wills for Smith and Sumner Counties, Tennessee. There are also copies of census records from the National Archives, and miscellaneous court records from other localities.
    - Carthage Courier, 3 July 1913 - 1968. (Box 95)
    - Various Smith County, TN Newspapers. (Box 95)
    - Population Schedules of the Sixth Census of the United States, 1840 - Tennessee (Smith, Stuart, and Sumner Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Seventh Census of the United States, 1850 - Pennsylvania (Fulton and Greene Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Seventh Census of the United States, 1850 - Tennessee (Smith County). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Eighth Census of the United States, 1860 - Tennessee (Smith and Stewart Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Ninth Census of the United States, 1870 - Tennessee (Smith amd Stewart Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Twelfth Census of the United States, 1900 - Indiana (Pulaski, Putnam, and Randolph Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Thirteenth Census of the United States, 1910 - Tennessee (Shelby and Smith Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Thirteenth Census of the United States, 1910 - Tennessee (Stewart, Sullivan, and Sumner Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Fourteenth Census of the United States, 1920 - Tennessee (Shelby and Smith Counties). (Box 96)
    - Population Schedules of the Fourteenth Census of the United States, 1920 - Tennessee (Sullivan and Sumner Counties). (Box 96)
    - Amelia County, VA - Marriage Bonds, 1735-1766. (Box 96)
    - Botetourt County, VA - Tithable Lists (Typed Transcriptions). (Box 96)
    - Nelson County, KY - Will Book, June 1784-February 1790. (Box 96)
    - Smith County, TN - Deed Books, April 1801-January 1902. (Box 97)
    - Smith County, TN - Index to Deed Books, 1801-1922. (Box 97)
    - Smith County, TN - Inventories, February 1823-May 1902. (Box 97)
    - Smith County, TN - Will Books, November 1805-August 1951. (Box 97)
    - Sumner County, TN - Deed Books, August 1793-November 1901. (Box 97)
    - Sumner County, TN - Index to Deed Books, 1787-1947. (Box 97)
    - Sumner County, TN - Inventories and Settlements, March 1808-May 1879. (Box 97)
    - Sumner County, TN - Will Books, July 1789-July 1904. (Box 97)
    - Wilson County, TN - Wills and Inventories, December 1802-April 1850. (Box 96)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1789-2010., Extent: 41 boxes. (Box 98-138)
  The Subject Files document Clay's interest in genealogical research, his involvement in numerous organizations, and his career as a reference archivist at the Library of Virginia from 1970 to 2001. The files include correspondence with family, friends, colleagues, and fellow genealogists and researchers. Some of the correspondence dates to when Clay was attending the University of Tennessee. The subject files also contain two groups (A-Z) of photocopies of marriages and obituaries of Clay family members and other individuals. There is genealogical research materials on the Gwaltney and Radford families, miscellaneous research notes, abstracts, and transcriptions, as well as clippings, diaries, maps, newsletters, recipes, scrapbooks, and yearbooks. There is a business ledger of William S. Alexander (1809-1876) of Dixon Springs, covering the years 1841-1845 and 1868-1872, detailing business transactions at his general store. There is a large amount of material relating to Clay's memberships in the Order of First Families of North Carolina, Order of First Families of Virginia, and the Virginia Genealogical Society. There is historical information on Dixon Springs and Smith County, Tennessee. Finally, there are memoranda, policies and procedures, brochures, forms, lists, and guides related to the collections at the Library of Virginia, and also genealogical research information for other states and countries. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Account Book, 1954-1957. (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Cary (Mrs. Donald C.). (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Address Book. (Box 163)
  - Addresses. (Box 98, Folder 3-7)
  - Agee, Dianne Davis. (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Aiken, Nancy (Mitchell Clay Descendant). (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Albert, Ethel E.. (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Albright, Lee. (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Alcorn, Maxine. (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Alexander-Beasley Family Scrapbook - Compiled by Edith Montfort Allen, 1999. (Box 98, Folder 13-14)
  - Algonkian Pronunciation Reference. (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Allen, David. (Box 99, Folder 1-2)
  - American University/NARA - Introduction to Modern Archives Administration, 7-18 June 1971. (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Betty Lou. (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Archives Manual. (Box 99, Folder 5-7)
  - Archives Reading Room. (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Arkansas. (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Arledge, Tacy A.. (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Arvantis, Lisa. (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Ballard - Tax Records. (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Bamman, Gale Williams. (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Barbados. (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Barr, Dixon A.. (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Barr, Willie C. (re: Esther Mai Haney). (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Bassett, Janice Kyle. (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Bates (Wilma C. Bass). (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Beasley, Elizabeth Wilson. (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - Beasley, Polly H.. (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - Bedke, Jane A.. (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Bedwell, Bessie M.. (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Carol Willsey. (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Bell, Mary McCampbell. (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Bentley, James R.. (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Bettis, Patricia. (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Biddle, Robert. (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Bigger, Jeanne. (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Black Genealogy. (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Blankenship, Michael (re: Ethel Evans Albert). (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Blumberg, Frederic and Natalie. (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Bockstruck, Lloyd DeWitt. (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Bogue, Linda. (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Boswell, Mary French. (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Bradshaw, Ray P.. (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Branch, Olive H.. (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Brayton, John Anderson. (Box 100, Folder 16)
  - Bresler. (Box 100, Folder 17)
  - Broach, Henry A.. (Box 100, Folder 18)
  - Brooks, Rev. R.D.. (Box 100, Folder 19)
  - Browder, Barbara. (Box 100, Folder 20)
  - Brummer, Marie. (Box 100, Folder 21)
  - Buckingham County Data (Austin-Twyman Papers, Swem Library). (Box 100, Folder 22)
  - Burned Records. (Box 100, Folder 23)
  - Burns, Loretta Elliott. (Box 100, Folder 24)
  - Burrell, Ruth. (Box 100, Folder 25)
  - Butler Family History. (Box 100, Folder 26-31)
  - Byers (Snoddy). (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Byington, Iris. (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Byrd. (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Cabell, Kathleen. (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Cage, Julia Kittrell. (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, 1964. (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Cal's Columns. (Box 101, Folder 7-8)
  - Camin, Betty J.. (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Campbell, Mary Elizabeth. (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Canada. (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Carlisle, Catherine. (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Carter, Hattie Donoho. (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Carthage Courier Articles. (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Carthage Courier Index. (Box 101, Folder 15-18)
  - Census. (Box 101, Folder 19)
  - Census Forms. (Box 101, Folder 20)
  - Census - Location of Originals. (Box 101, Folder 21)
  - Central Virginia Genealogical Association. (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Certification. (Box 101, Folder 23)
  - Channel Islands - Research. (Box 101, Folder 24)
  - Charts. (Box 101, Folder 25)
  - Charts (Radford, Gwaltney, Ross, Craig). (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Chestnut, Paul. (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Record (Gifts Received), 1979. (Box 163)
  - Churches. (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Jewell. (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Clark, Mrs. Jewell - Notes. (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Wendy. (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Clay, Charles Ransom. (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Clay, Claude Dixon. (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Clay, Erskine. (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Clay, George Marston (Oklahoma). (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Clay, George R.. (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Clay, James Carrington. (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Clay, James Denton. (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Clay, J.E. (Pikeville, TN). (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Clay, Maurice. (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Clay, Maurice Kenneth. (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - Clay, Ohlen F.. (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - Clay, Oster Lee. (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - Clay, Ray. (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - Clay, Roy U.. (Box 102, Folder 20)
  - Chestnut, Susan E. Chandley. (Box 102, Folder 21)
  - Clay, T.C. (Texas). (Box 102, Folder 22)
  - Clay, William. (Box 102, Folder 23)
  - Clay, William Corbett. (Box 102, Folder 24)
  - Clay-Dove, William. (Box 102, Folder 25)
  - Clement, Bonnie. (Box 102, Folder 26)
  - Clemmer, Gregg. (Box 102, Folder 27)
  - Clippings. (Box 102, Folder 28)
  - Clippings. (Box 169, Folder 7-8)
  - Clippings - Confederate/Civil War. (Box 102, Folder 29)
  - Clippings - Cox/Allen. (Box 102, Folder 30)
  - Clippings - Dixon Springs. (Box 102, Folder 31)
  - Clippings - Families. (Box 102, Folder 32)
  - Clippings - Gann. (Box 102, Folder 33)
  - Clippings - History. (Box 102, Folder 34)
  - Clippings - Library. (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Clippings - Marriages. (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Clippings - Ross. (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Clippings - Teachers. (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Clippings - U.D.C.. (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Clippings - World War I. (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1986, 1989-1999. (Box 103, Folder 7-18)
  - Clippings, 2000-2001. (Box 104, Folder 1-2)
  - Coldest Summer. (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Cole, Helen Hutson. (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Cook, Bettie Cummings. (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Cook, Joyce. (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Cook, Mamie Fuller. (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Cook, Nancy Clay. (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Copies for Nancy Cook. (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Cornett, Robert F. Jr.. (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Cornwell, Thompson R.. (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (A-L), 1954-1960. (Box 104, Folder 12-20)
  - Correspondence (M-Z), 1954-1960. (Box 105, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence (Pre-1962). (Box 105, Folder 8-11)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969. (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979. (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1990. (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1991-2002. (Box 106, Folder 1-7)
  - Corum, Frank. (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Corum, Katherine Beasley. (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Courts. (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Courts-Tennessee 1991. (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Creekmore, Pollyanna. (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Cross, Mrs. Horace C.. (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Crumpler, Laura. (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Cuthbert, Hibernia H. 1991. (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - D.A.R. Library. (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Henry Braxton Jr.. (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Davis-Mann. (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Virginia Lee Hutcheson. (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Denney, Joseph C.. (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Detroit Society Publication - Trial Text. (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1957. (Box 162)
  - Diary (Enclosures), 1957. (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1958. (Box 163)
  - Diary (Enclosures), 1958. (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1960. (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1964. (Box 164)
  - Diary (Mildred Gwaltney - European Trip), 1966. (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 2003. (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Dietrich, E.A. "Gene". (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Dinwiddie County Historical Society. (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Directory of Repositories in Virginia, 1988. (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Dixon Springs/Smith County. (Box 107, Folder 15-17)
  - Dixon Springs/Smith County. (Box 108, Folder 1-4)
  - Dixon Springs/Smith County - Evelyn Ross Notes. (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Dixon Springs Cemetery. (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - "Dixona". (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Dorman, John Frederick. (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Dow, Elizabeth Pugh Carr Lawrence. (Box 108, Folder 9-13)
  - Downing, Elizabeth K.. (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Doyle, James W.. (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Duke, Sally (Evelyn's Cousin). (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - East Tennessee Historical Society. (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Shore (Nancy Garrett's Talk). (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Edwards, Conley. (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Elliott, Katherine. (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Ellison, Esther. (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Emerson, Margaret Dotson. (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Emery, Margaret. (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Engelbart, Betty. (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - England Trip, 1997. (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - English Research. (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Enoch, Mary Beth Beasley. (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Ephemera. (Box 168)
  - Evans, Mary. (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Family Ancestor Charts (Blank). (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Family Tree DNA. (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - Flanders, Eleanore. (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - Fleet, Beverly - Notes Given to RYC by Isobel Inman. (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - Form Statements. (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - Forsythe, Warren L.. (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Foster, Calvin. (Box 109, Folder 19)
  - Fountain, Doris K.. (Box 109, Folder 20)
  - Frashier, Anne and Lloyd (Young Family). (Box 109, Folder 21)
  - Fraustein, Rebah M.. (Box 109, Folder 22)
  - Freeman, Clyde. (Box 109, Folder 23)
  - French Research. (Box 109, Folder 24)
  - Fulton, James C.. (Box 109, Folder 25)
  - Gann, Aunt Mamie Clay. (Box 109, Folder 26)
  - Gardiner, Lawrence. (Box 109, Folder 27)
  - Gardner, Mrs. O.K.. (Box 109, Folder 28)
  - Garrett, Anne Wright. (Box 109, Folder 29)
  - Garrett, Dr. Sam Young. (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Gaylord Preservation Pathfinders. (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Geiger, Alice F.. (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Gnealogical Charts. (Box 171, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Notes - Articles. (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical Research - England Trips. (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Genealogical Research - English Records. (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical Research - France. (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Genealogical Research - Marriage Records. (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Genealogical Research in Other States - Guides, etc.. (Box 110, Folder 9)